<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Automation project</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home Automation project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:45:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rabbit feeder v2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/food02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 17:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/food02/</guid>
      <description>IoT enabled rabbit feeder, automatic and controllable via Internet.
Github repository: https://github.com/conejoninja/home_food
Idea and motivation Learn from the experience and improve the previous versions of the feeder.
As with the old prototype, the feeder will wake up each 15 minutes, send the temperature and humidity to a server and check if it&amp;rsquo;s time to feed the monsters. It&amp;rsquo;s as autonomous as possible (it will feed them if it&amp;rsquo;s time, even if there&amp;rsquo;s no internet connection).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 17:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/</guid>
      <description> List of devices connected to the network.
Devices  Food01: IoT enabled Rabbit feeder, autonomous and controllable via internet. Food02: Second version of the IoT enabled Rabbit feeder, autonomous and controllable via internet.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rabbit feeder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/food01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2017 17:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/devices/food01/</guid>
      <description>IoT enabled rabbit feeder, automatic and controllable via Internet.
Github repository: https://github.com/conejoninja/home_food
Idea and motivation The main idea was to be able to feed these two little rascals even when I&amp;rsquo;m not at home. Twice a day, a small quantity at breakfast and a bigger one for dinner (non-spoiled rabbits are supposed to eat timothy during the day when they are not sleeping). I would like to also measure the temperature in case it gets too hot, since rabbits don&amp;rsquo;t do well on hot weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 17:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/home/</guid>
      <description>To log all the sensor data and be able to process it later, we use what we call Home. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Go and made of different configurable module. The two principal tasks are to log the sensor data in the Logger and serve it via the API.
Logger Source code
Save sensor data and other information from the MQTT network in a database.
API Source code
Create a HTTP server and listen for requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 17:45:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/protocol/</guid>
      <description>Simple protocol to discover and communicate with IoT devices on a network. The devices communicate with each other through the same central server(s) (a single server or a mesh), that may or may not be in the same local network. This makes possible the communication of devices in different physical networks.
Discovery of devices Devices that join the network will broadcast their description. The message will be send to the discovery channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Automation project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 18:28:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/</guid>
      <description>Amateur project to automate a few task in my home and communicate with some IoT devices. I used a mix of languages, frameworks and platforms. I will try to document as much as possible, but remember, this is an amateur project.
Global view In order to interact together, devices communicates with each other through a MQTT server using a custom JSON-based protocol. Besides the devices, there are a few &amp;ldquo;modules&amp;rdquo; too, those modules are programs that consume the MQTT messages, perform actions based of information and allow human interaction (Web, App).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/home/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/home/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Contributing Guidelines Code of Conduct This project is intended to be a safe, welcoming space for collaboration. All contributors are expected to adhere to the Contributor Covenant code of conduct. Thank you for being kind to each other!.
Contributions welcome! Before spending lots of time on something, ask for feedback on your idea first!
Please search issues and pull requests (or in any of the related projects) before adding something new!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>